<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<book title="Dwarven Kingdom History">
Author: Kiwi
edited by AlddrA
<page>
<title>Dwarven Kingdom History</title>
</page>
<page>
<text>
The Dwarven Kingdom is one of the longest standing factions on Alroth, next to the Orcs. Originally, the dwarves lived in what they called the Gara - their homeland. This area still stands today and is known as the Dwarven Lands. The official Dwarven Kingdom began in the southwest. Though there is also history of dwarves in Valunde, it is widely believed that Golron I started his Kingdom in Lothend. Lothend was the land south of the largest mountain range in the Dwarven Lands called Thunder Mountain. Golron expanded his Kingdom into the Northern Reach (the land North of Thunder Mountain) and into the Southern Expanse (to the south east of Thunder Mountain). 

When the Dwarves became rich enough, the orcs of Blackstone Mountain attacked the Dwarven Kingdom, and the First Orc War began. The fighting was bloody and relentless. Golron fought and slew many Orcs, but he could not withstand the constant onslaught. He knew the orcs would overtake them eventually. It was at this time Golron I had his first revelation. Meeka, the god of defense, guided him into the mountains and showed him how his mines could be used to create fortifications enabling the dwarves to survive the attacks and eventually the Orcs of Blackstone Mountain dwindled.

Sadly, the Orcs in Valunde had all but destroyed the Dwarves that lived there. Refugees fled to the West (the area now called Drakensbane). That is when the Orcs of the east discovered Golron I's Kingdom. Thus the Second Orc War began. Again the fighting was bloody, but eventually the dwarves won Blackstone Mountain. After many years of siege, the orcs gave up the fight against Golron's Kingdom. Golron I continued the fight until the orcs were driven back to Valunde. Once the dwarves firmly held the border between Blackstone (Drakensbane) and Valunde, Golron I declared this war over. 
</text>
</page>
<page>
<text>
Many years went by while Golron rebuilt his Kingdom. They fought against the orcs for many generations, eventually taking back Valunde. As the Dwarven Kingdom began to creep steadily along the mountains, it soon overtook a large portion of Alroth. Never straying too far from the mountains, the Dwarven Kingdom now stretched into the Farnorth and some ways into the East. Eventually, all of the mountainous regions belonged to the dwarves. 

Even though the Dwarven Kingdom had grown very strong and wealthy, the orcs continued to be a problem. Orcs openly opposed them and would fight over the smallest parcels of land, forcing the dwarves to stay close to the mountains. The Humans discovered the Dwarven Kingdom when the dwarves had driven the orcs from most of Alroth. They had also been beset upon by the orcs. Golron III pledged allegiance to the Nation of Men to garner their help in driving the orcs back. The Dwarven Kingdom now stretched East and West, and almost all Lands were under the influence of the dwarves.

The Dwarven Kingdom flourished for many years. Then the Nation of Men went to war with the Dwarven Kingdom because they wanted more land to grow but the dwarves were restricting them. The Men proved their might and eventually took over the East, though they could not take the Mountains from the dwarves. 
</text>
</page>
<page>
<text>
Then the Orchan Alliance came down from the Farnorth. Orchans are large, tusked humanoids in League with the orcs. They were unknown to the dwarves until they declared war. They took the land in the West away from the Dwarves and continued to fight in the North. 

The Dwarven Kingdom, the Nation of Men, and the Orchan Alliance all fought and struggled to retain their freedom, but for the most part, control of the Land remained with the dwarves. Although the Dwarven Kingdom continued to keep its hold on the mountains, they did lose a vast majority of its open land in the North and West. Shortly after, the Draegoni Dominion came to Alroth. They were a ferocious force to contend with. They fought and killed everyone in the Orchan territories in the West. Galrin I was High King at this time. He wisely decided that it would be best for the dwarves to retreat back into the mountains. They sold outlying pieces of land to the humans and gave up land to the Draegoni Dominion. The Dwarven Kingdom shrunk all the way back down to Valunde, an event known as the Diminishing. Most of the population moved to Thunder Mountain. The Dwarves had cut off trade with the humans by this time. Although they had vast stores of goods, it was not well rationed. Consequently the famine that followed decimated the population. Few dwarves lived outside the mountains, but those that did were constantly under threat of Draegoni invasion.
</text>
</page>
<page>
	<text>
After Skyfall, the dwarves came back out of the mountains. They reclaimed and repurchased old Lands around Thunder Mountain and Valunde. Lands have exchanged hands many times throughout the years following Skyfall. The Dwarven Lands as we know them today have been this way for many years. It is hard to tell if the wars we currently experience will go down in history as major events, or if they will mix into the obscurity of another feudal age.
</text>
</page>
</book>
