<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<book title="Glingor History">
<page>
<title>Glingor History</title>
</page>
Author: Kiwi
Edited by Alddra
<page>
<text>
Glingor was wild and unoccupied for a very long time. But when Golron's Kingdom discovered Glingor, there was already a small population of humans. The dwarves of Valunde are said to have traded with these humans whenever possible, but for the most part their connection was cut off by orcs.

The humans say that the orcs were very oppressive in the past. The human population never got any bigger than a few villages. They were often forced to a nomadic lifestyle because of the orc's pillaging and burnings. 

The humans finally managed to wrest control of Glingor from the orcs around the time of the Second Orc War. The orcs had been weakened and divided as a result of their warring ways. King Halden began to build his Western Kingdom as soon as the fighting stopped. 

Many generations passed, but the Western Kingdom prevailed. The crown of the Western Kingdom was passed down nineteen times when King Hafeld arose to power. King Hafeld fought to unite the Kingdoms of Men, which was vital to their survival during the Draegoni Dominion. Many troops were lent to King Hafeld, who helped keep the orcs from passing through to the East. 
</text>
</page>

<page>
<text>
After the Skyfall, the dwarves purchased an area of land from Lord Brenn and called it Glingor. King Jaen was outraged at the agreement, which had gone through without his approval. He declared war on the Dwarven Kingdom to take back Glingor. Kelfin Farquen of Valunde stepped up to lead a prominent force of dwarves to defend Glingor. Kirin Nightmane and Stivin of Lothend also helped in the fight.

The war was a huge success for the dwarves. They were simply better supplied and had more troops to spare. King Jaen did not have the support of the Human Nations, and could not afford to fight for very long. 

The dwarves built a solid stone wall to defend Glingor from any further human attacks. Clan Farquen was named a noble house, and Kelfin's son Kefwin became the Lord of Glingor. Since the Glingor War, there have been many squabbles over the land of Glingor. Humans have attacked off and on, and recently they successfully took control of the wall in the East.
</text>
</page>
</book> 
