<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<book title="Rhoelind and Morog History">
Author: Kiwi
------edited by AlddrA-----
<page>
<title>Rhoelind and Morog (Southern Expanse) History</title>
</page>
<page>
<text>
Rhoelind and Morog are part of the Southern Expanse. The Expanse was controlled by the orcs for a very long time. After the First Orc War, Golron's people began to pioneer eastward into the Expanse. They found that this area was very rich in minerals and ores. 

Typically Dwarves mine in the mountains, but the Expanse was vast and had many deposits beneath its surface. Large tunnel networks were developed and maintained by the dwarves. During the Second Orc War, these tunnels proved very useful for the transportation of goods and troops, and their defenses became unbreachable in some areas.  However, as the Second Orc War came to a close, some of the tunnels were taken over by orcs. Golron I allowed this to happen in order to force the bulk of the remaining orcs underground and to prevent the sacrifice of more dwarven lives. Although the orcs still come out on occasion, the dwarves keep a watchful eye to ensure they remain in their new home.

The tunnels allowed for Thunder Mountain to become a central hub for storing goods from the Southern Expanse. When the Draegoni came, most of the dwarves took refuge underground. The Expanse was split into two territories; Morog and Rhoelind. Both of these territories had been very populated before the Draegoni Dominion.
</text>
</page>

<page>
<text>
With the fall of the Draegoni Dominion came the Skyfall. Meteors struck the land all over Alroth. Most of the impacts were concentrated around the center of the Draegoni Dominion in the North, but Rhoelind also suffered major damage. A large meteor had landed almost directly in its center. The resulting earthquake caused most of the Dwarven tunnel networks to collapse.

Settlements, mines and thousands of dwarves were lost - buried. The collapse of the main tunnels can be seen on the surface of Morog, Rhoelind and even Braigor. It was such a tragic catastrophe that the dwarves have refused to uncover some of the old tunnels. They consider it taboo to disturb the dead that were entombed. 

There has been some recovery. Braigor was well maintained, surviving the meteor strike to a large degree; and since Kilron Hammerfist was appointed as the Lord of Morog, it has started to become a worthwhile place to live. Rhoelind on the other hand, has become mostly unlivable. The grass around the meteor has never grown back, making the land almost dead. The material inside the meteor has proven to be deadly to most forms of life. 

Orcs and goblins have moved into what is left of the old tunnels. Though the people have tried to reclaim some of the old mines, Rhoelind will never be what it once was. Recently, the appointed regent, Lady Ahldra has gone missing. No one knows where she could have gone. There haven't even been any sightings since she disappeared. 
</text>
</page>
</book>
